

Aorten Amundsen

Arne Fjellbus veg 10C, 7033 Trondheim, Norway

□ (+47) 458 83 216 | 🗷 m.amundsen@pm.me | 🏕 mortenamundsen.me | 🖸 netr0m | 🛅 mortenkamundsen

Summary.

Currently working as a Security Engineer @ Sportradar. I have experience with Security Operations, development, scripting/automation, and computer security, and an interest in infrastructure (as code). I'm curious, and I love to learn and solve challenges.

For my Master's thesis, I developed a system to automate the process of handling user incident reports based on Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing.

Education

NTNU (Norwegian University of Science and Technology)

Gjøvik, Norway

MSc in Information Security

Aug. 2018 - Jun. 2020

- Track of study: Information Security Management
- See my LinkedIn profile for all courses.

UiA (University of Agder)

Kristiansand, Norway

B.S. IN IT AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS

Aug. 2015 - Jun. 2018

Jul. 2020 - present

Jun. 2018 - Jul. 2020

• See my LinkedIn profile for all courses.

Skills_

Security Application Security, Reverse Engineering, Threat Hunting, Log Analysis, Risk Management

Tools Splunk, Vectra, Darktrace, Microsoft Defender ATP, Sophos UTM,

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Git, Ansible, AWS, Puppet, Proxmox

Back-end Express, Django, Flask, REST API

Operative Systems Linux, Windows

Programming Python, Node.js, JAVA, C#, Golang **Scripting** Python, JavaScript, Bash, PowerShell

Languages Norwegian, English

Experience_

Sportradar AS Trondheim, Norway

· Development of security automation tools

• Defensive Ops

SECURITY ENGINEER

- Threat Hunting / OSINT
- Incident handling
- · Risk Assessments • Security Policies
- Application Security Assessments
- Red-teaming Operations
- · Phishing Simulation

Sportradar AS Trondheim, Norway

Information Security Analyst

• Part-time employment working remotely. Full-time during vacations.

- Development of security automation tools
- Threat Hunting / OSINT
- Incident handling
- Risk Assessments
- Security Policies
- · Application Security Assessments

APRIL 19, 2021 MORTEN AMUNDSEN · CURRICULUM VITAE Decentralize IT Kristiansand, Norway

LEAD DEVELOPER Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2018

- Internship as a full-stack developer.
- Developed a cross-platform smartphone application based on the Steem blockchain, as well as a RESTful API backend.
- Working with the technologies Xamarin. Forms, React. js, Node. js, MongoDB, AWS and nginx.

University of Agder Kristiansand, Norway

ASSISTANT TEACHER

Jan. - May. 2018, Jan. - Jun. 2017

- Assistant Teacher in the course IS-213; Open Source Software.
- Assistant Teacher in the course IS-110; Object Oriented Programming 2.

Elektroimportøren AS

Trondheim, Norway

Warehouse worker Jun. 2016 - Jan. 2020

- Part-time employment during vacations.
- Warehouse worker, seller and cashier.
- Working with logistics, order handling, Visma, sales and cashier.

ICA Supermarked Nardo Trondheim, Norway

Cashier

Apr. 2014 - Aug. 2015

· Part-time employment as a cashier.

Televita AS Trondheim, Norway

TELEMARKETER

Jan. 2014 - Apr. 2014

• Part-time employment as a telemarketer.

Certifications

AWS SECURITY ESSENTIALS

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Online

SECURITY ENGINEERING ON AWS Oct. 2020

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Online Sep. 2020

The University of Nebraska at Omaha

Omaha, Nebraska, U.S.

CERTIFICATE IN IT ADMINISTRATION

Jan. 2017

References_

References can be provided upon request. My friends, colleagues and leaders will describe me as engaged, goal-oriented and hard-working. They will also say that I take great pride in the work I deliver, and that I don't quit until the job is done.